Mosharaf Hossain

Junior Software Engineer

+880 1745634724 mosharaf111hossain@gmail.com
★ Dhaka, Bangladesh
in/mosharaf-hossain github.com/Mosharaf456

Profile

Skillful and hardworking person, passionate about programming. Can work on any software platform. And also best skills in quickly adaptable new technologies.

Areas of Expertise

DevOps - Full Stack Web - LAMP Stack - Database - API - Machine Learning - Computer Networking - Linux

Work Experience

Junior Software Engineer, Brotecs Technologies Ltd.

02/2023 - present

- Implemented microservice strategies, leading to revenue generation in 2024 using the LAMPA stack.
- Developed scalable apps using DevOps, React.js, Next.js, and Laravel, Ci4, improving system performance by 25%.
- Optimized MySQL and MariaDB databases, reducing query time by 15%.

Intern Software Engineer, Brotecs Technologies Ltd.

08/2022 - 01/2023

• Enhanced software performance: Refactored legacy codebase by applying OOP in PHP, resulting in a 50% reduction in load times and a 20% increase in application efficiency.

Teaching Assistant, American International University-Bangladesh,

05/2021 - 08/2021

• Improved student programming skills: Successfully guided over 200 students through algorithm programming concepts, leading to a 30% increase in course completion rates.

Professional & Personal Projects

- Aeronautical Ground Communication Gateway (2023-2024)- AGCG
- Skylar License Web (Jan. 2024) Skylar
- Charity Defosco/Alorkoli web (May. 2024) Alorkoli

Education

BSc. CSE - **Computer Science**, American International University-Bangladesh, **Dhaka**, **Bangladesh** 2017-2021 Relevant Courses: C, C++, C#, Java, PHP, JS and data mining, Machine learning, Data Visualization, Python, Statistics, Math, Computer Networking & Thesis on Fake News detection on facebook by using machine learning.

Skills

- Microservice & DevOps: Docker, Docker Compose, Networking, Jenkins-CI/CD pipelines, Linux, Git
- Full Stack: JS[ES6], ReactJs, Next.js, PHP, Codelgniter, Laravel, Websocket, REST API development, SOAP API, MYSQL, Mariadb
- Machine Learning: Python, scikit-learn, Pandas, Numpy, Statistical ML
- **Soft Skills:** Pro-active, Presentation, Planning, Organized, Creative Problem-Solving, Teamwork, Active Listening, Adaptability, Analytical Thinking

Languages

• Bangla [Native]

• English [Fluent]